Guide to the Stanford University, Residential Education, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Residential Education, records
1956-2012
SC1170
Stanford University. Office of Residential Education. Crothers Global Citizenship Program.
13.5 Linear feet (9 cartons)
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
This collection was transferred to Stanford University, Special Collections in 2012, 2013.
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Biographical/Historical note
Residential Education is responsible for developing the policies, programs, and staffing which support the intellectual, educational, and community-building activities in student residences. The Residential Education program provides Stanford undergraduates a small community experience within a large research university.
Scope and Contents
Files include Residential Education directories, training and orientation guides, program and committee files, media files, news clippings, reports, and photographs. Also included are files related to particular dormitories and residences.
Access Terms
Residential education; Stanford University--Students.
Collection Contents
- Records, Accession ARCH-2012-028
  - Res. Ed. Reports (1 of 4), 1971-1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Res. Ed. Reports (2 of 4), 1971-1984 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Res. Ed. Reports (3 of 4), 1971-1984 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Res. Ed. Reports (4 of 4), 1971-1984 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Residence Program Summaries (1 of 4), 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Residence Program Summaries (2 of 4), 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Residence Program Summaries (3 of 4), 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Residence Program Summaries (4 of 4), 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Residence Program Summaries (1 of 4), 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Residence Program Summaries (2 of 4), 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Residence Program Summaries (3 of 4), 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Residence Program Summaries (4 of 4), 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Residence Program Summaries (1 of 4), 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Residence Program Summaries (2 of 4), 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Residence Program Summaries (3 of 4), 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Residence Program Summaries (4 of 4), 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Residence Program Summaries (1 of 2), 2001-2002 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Residence Program Summaries (2 of 2), 2001-2002 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Background Info on the Office of Res. Ed. (1 of 2), 2005 Fall (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Background Info on the Office of Res. Ed. (2 of 2), 2005 Fall (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Res. Ed. Reports (1 of 2), 1971-1984 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Res. Ed. Reports (2 of 2), 1971-1984 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Report on the Task Force on Fraternities & Sororities, 1988 Jan (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Task Force Residental Program (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Residence Housing Proposals (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Res. Ed. Info Packet, circa 2003-2005 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Housing Rates, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Res. Fellow Apartment Info, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - RF Historical List (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Residential Education, 2000 May (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Summary Report of Academic Theme House Self Studies (1 of 2), 1998 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Summary Report of Academic Theme House Self Studies (2 of 2), 1998 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Proposal for an African American Studies Themed House (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Riddell Fund Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Casa Zapata - Stern Hall (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Historical Directories/RFs/DAs/ Central Office/ Field Office, 1975-1989 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Ujamaa, circa 1988 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - UCMI Press Articles (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Okada Film/ Racism Clippings (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Casa Zapata Newsclips, 1986 Feb 1-Dec 31 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Casa Zapata: Newsclips, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Bridge Media, 1991-1995 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Diversity: Press Articles, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Diversity Articles: Siezing the Torch, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Diversity: Press Articles, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Diversity: Press Articles, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Alcohol: Clippings from Daily Concerning New Policy (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Casa Zapata: Newsclips, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Casa Zapata: Newsclips, 1989-1992 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Ethnic Theme Houses: Casa Zapata - Mural Article, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Ujamaa Incident Media File, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Theme Houses: Press Articles (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Newspaper Clippings: Theme/Focus (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Multiculturalism: Press Articles (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Clippings (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Residence Staff Directory, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Programing Calendar for Stanford Residence Staff, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Residence Directory, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Residence Directory, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Residence Directory, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Residence Directory, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Residence Directory, 1995-1996 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Residence Directory, 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Residence Directory, 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Residence Directory, 2000-2001 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Residence Directory, 2000-2001 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Residence Directory & Residence Staff Calendar, 2001-2002 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Residence Directory & Residence Staff Calendar, 2001-2002 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Residence Directory, 2002-2003 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Residence Directory, 2003-2004 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Residential Staff Directory, 2004-2005 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Residential Ed. Staff Directory, 2005-2006 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Residential Staff Calendar, 2008-2009 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - RA Training Binder, 2007-2008 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - STEER (Stanford Taskforce Evaluating Eduation in Residence) Binder, 2005 Fall (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Undergraduate Housing Master Plan - Space Details, 2009 Apr (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - PAC-10 Housing Officers Meeting, 2008 Feb 27-29 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Jeanne Clery Act Compliance: A Collaborative Team Approach - Participant's Manual, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Studies/ Histories, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Reports, circa 1990 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - RA/CA Application Packet, 2007-2008 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - STEER (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Housing Master Plan (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Task Force Report (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Media Files Index (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Media Files, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Media Files (1 of 2), 1985 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Media Files (2 of 2), 1985 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Media Files (1 of 2), 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Media Files (2 of 2), 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Media Files (1 of 2), 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Media Files (2 of 2), 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Media Files (1 of 2), 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Media Files (2 of 2), 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Media Files (1 of 3), 1988 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Media Files (2 of 3), 1988 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Media Files (3 of 3), 1988 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Media Files (1 of 2), 1988-1990 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Media Files (2 of 2), 1988-1990 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Media Files (1 of 2), 1989 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Media Files (2 of 2), 1989 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Media Files (1 of 2), 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Media Files (2 of 2), 1981-1982 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Media Files (1 of 2), 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Media Files (2 of 2), 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Media Files (1 of 2), 1974-1977 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Media Files (2 of 2), 1974-1977 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Media Files (1 of 2), 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Media Files (2 of 2), 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Media Files (1 of 2), 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Media Files (2 of 2), 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Media Files (1 of 2), 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Media Files (2 of 2), 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Media Files (1 of 2), 1983-1984 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Media Files (2 of 2), 1983-1984 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Media Files (1 of 2), 1983-1984 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Media Files (2 of 2), 1983-1984 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Media Files (1 of 2), 1984-1985 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Media Files (2 of 2), 1984-1985 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Media Files, circa 2000s (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Media Files, circa 2000s (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Excerpts from the Final Reports for the Grape Policy (1 of 3), 1995 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Excerpts from the Final Reports for the Grape Policy (2 of 3), 1995 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Excerpts from the Final Reports for the Grape Policy (3 of 3), 1995 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Resnet Symposium, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Media Files, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Centennial Campaign, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Directories, 1979-1984 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Grapes (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Stanford Facebook, 2002-2003 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - History of Ethnic Theme Dorms (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Campus Disruption - President Office Takeover, 15 May 1989 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Res. Ed. Logo (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Res. Ed. Directories (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Media Files, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Press Clippings, 1973-1974 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Grapes Policy (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Grapes Eduation Committee (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Grapes Education Program - Evaluations for RAs/ RFs, 1998-1999 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Approaching Stanford, 1999-2000 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Budget Cuts: Press Clippings, 1992 Jan. - 1992 Feb. (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Budget Cuts: APC Press Clippings, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Committees: Grapes Policy - Implementation (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Committees: Grapes Report (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - New Student Orientation Results, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Committees: Grapes Policy - Grape Workers & Farmers Coalition (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Branner (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Resources Manual, 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Resources Manual, 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Additional Records, Accession ARCH-2014-003
  - Residences, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Florence Moore Hall, 1956-1957 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Florence Moore Hall, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Florence Moore Hall, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Florence Moore Hall, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Florence Moore Hall, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Otero Residence, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Trancos Residence, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Cedro Residence, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Stern Houses, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Larkin residence, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Serra residence, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Toyon Residence (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Roble Hall, 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Storey Residence, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Manzanita, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Residences Lagunita - Ujamaa (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - The Row (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Orienataion Guides, 1977-1997 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Paper of College, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Student Initiatives (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Reports, 1975-1988 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Report, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Co-operative Living (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Cross-Cultural Residences (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Multicultural Report, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - LGBT, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Stanford Facebook, 2010-2011 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - New Student Orientation Guides, 2007-2011 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - RA Training Reference Guide, 2010-2011 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Resident Staff Calendar, 2009-2010 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Resident Assistant Refernece Book, 2009-2010 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - (not labeled) RA Training, 2009-2010 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Training Material for Resident Staff (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Rape Tape - Res. Educ., 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Working Against Rape and Women's Self-Defense, 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Jeanne Le Page "Rethinking Rape", 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - Faces of Community, 1998; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Photographic Slides: Abusive Images of Women in mass Media (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Approaching Stanford Handbook, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Training Material for Resident Staff, 1993-2009 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Training Material for Resident Staff, 1989-1993 (Box 2, Folder 5)